# Rehman Ali

### Software Engineer CGPA 3.44

I am motivated professional experienced with Web Development specially in MERN stack. To enhance my professional skills and working capacities with full determination carry on with my aim of becoming a successful software engineer for well growing company.

✓ dev.rehmanali@gmail.com

Lahore, Pakistan

github.com/dev-rehmanali

03057397297

in linkedin.com/in/rehman-ali-673342177

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Software Engineer** OUH Dock

11/2022 - Present

# Full Stack Developer (Remote)

We Clone You (Contract)

09/2022 - 12/2022

San Diego, California, United States

Achievements/Tasks

- Started working as a full stack developer to develop an (MVP) of a project management tool to compete the market trends.
- Firstly worked on developing real time chat and video calling feature using third party providers. Developed Team Management module for sharing, discussing tasks and also assigning tasks to other developers.
- Designed a micro-frontend architecture for the whole application. Throughout the project worked with multiple technologies described as skills.

# Software Engineer

### Kinectro Technology Solutions and Services

12/2021 - 11/2022

Lahore, Pakistan

Achievements/Tasks

- Crypto API Integration.
- I have worked on NodeJs API Development.
- UI Development with React JS.
- Integration of GraphQL / Apollo Server and Client in the Application.
- Global State Management Using Redux Workflow.
- Styling with SASS/CSS/Tailwind CSS.
- Integration of UI with the API.
- API Test Automation using Chai and Mocha.
- Deployment on the Web Server(EC2).

# **Freelancing**Remote

02/2019 - 11/2021

Achievements/Tasks

- Fee Management System API with NodeJs
- Fee Management System UI using React with Backend integrations
- Food Order Application with Java and JavaFX

### **SKILLS**



### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

Library Visitors Counting and Analysis Using CCTV (2020 - 2021)

- Dataset preparation.
- Face Recognition Using Google's Face-net.
- Visitor Counting (Both Incoming and outgoing).
- Web Application.

### Pharmacy Module (2020 - 2021)

 In this module we made a CRUD application for the Pharmacy as a course project.

#### UI of E learning Portal

- In this project i made UI of E learning Portal for KG

### LANGUAGES

English

Urdu

Full Professional Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

### **EDUCATION**

BS Software Engineering

GIFT University Gujranwala

10/2017 - 11/2021